

Soma Utsumi

Senior Software Engineer (Platform Engineering)

- Tokyo, Japan
- github.com/soma00333
- soma00333.notion.site/Soma-Utsumi-32fff212315a4e9d894b704d52b23074

SUMMARY

I'm a Senior Software Engineer with 6+ years of professional experience in Platform Engineering in Tokyo, Japan.

I engaged in the backend developments for enterprise applications and the operation of cloud infrastructures with high-security requirements.

I am proficient in developing microservices with Go and managing infrastructures using Kubernetes.

SKILLS

Site Reliability Engineer

- SLI/SLO
- Datadog
- Observability
- Product Security
- Performance Improvement
- Incident Management

Platform Engineer

- GCP
- AWS
- Kubernetes
- Terraform
- CI/CD
- Developer Experience
- Cost Management

Backend Engineer

- Go
- gRPC
- PostgreSQL
- MySQL
- Microservice

LANGUAGES

- Japanese(Native)
- English(Business)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2024-04 -

Freelance, Site Reliability Engineer in AI/LLM Division

Present

LayerX Inc.

- I was involved in developing enterprise applications and infrastructures for the top 10 financial institutions in Japan.
- I deployed applications and infrastructures to the enterprise client's environments using the closed network, ensuring compliance with the highest security standards.

2023-11 -

Freelance, Platform Engineer

Present

enechain Corporation

- I was involved in the operation of GKE clusters with over 40 nodes and more than 350 pods.
- I created manifest and Terraform generator tools for developers, accelerating microservice development and cutting coding time by 90%.
- I rebuilt the Terraform infrastructures to improve execution speed and cost efficiency, resulting in a 50% reduction in execution time and a 50% reduction in costs.
- I standardized repository structures and branch strategies for manifests and applications, resulting in a 20% improvement in CI/CD speed.
- I introduced telepresence to the dev cluster to improve the developer experience of microservice developments.
- I redesigned the access control policies with high governance and security standards to ensure compliance with audits for the government.

2019-04 -Present

CTO

Industry Technology Inc.

- I developed the backend for the enterprise application, which provides over 60 services(.protos) to the largest real estate companies in Japan.
- I deployed applications and infrastructures that ensured enterprise security and governance standards.
- I migrated a legacy MySQL 5.7 to MySQL 8.0 (500 QPS), improving cost efficiency and performance.
- I designed SLIs and SLOs based on CUJ and created dashboards and monitors, which resulted in incident mitigation and early bug detection.
- I migrated from a modular monolith (100 RPS) to microservices, resulting in an increased release frequency.

EDUCATION

2014/04 -

Bachelor of Engineering

2018/03

The University of Tokyo

 I designed a preoperative evaluation system for elderly patients using a generalized linear model.

2014/07 -

English courses in Los Angeles

2014/09

EF International Language Campus

• I studied English in LA.